# Osamu Ito

Glen Mills, PA | 302-668-6681 | mr.samito@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Portfolio/Website

## **FULL STACK APPLICATION DEVELOPER**

Excited Software Engineer with experience in Ruby/Ruby on Rails, React, JavaScript, SQL databases, and RESTful API architecture. Previous background in Apparel Production Management. Possess strong skills in communication, management, and working with cross-functional teams/departments to complete projects/orders for company growth.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript (ES6), React.js, Ruby/ Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku, Git

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

### Be@rbrick&Mortar - Github | Demo

Ecommerce app where users can view and buy Be@rbrick art figures

- Users can create accounts/use logins
- Users can search for specific figures by name, and add/delete items from cart
- Mock payment added
- Implemented React.js frontend, Ruby on Rails backend, PostgreSQL, react-bootstrap and custom CSS.

# Game Invader - Github | Demo

Game review app which allows users to view and provide feedback/reviews on games which are in our database

- Users can create/update/delete accounts, and create/delete reviews.
- Utilized Ruby and Sinatra to help control backend and server side frameworks
- Used React for front end/client side rendering and interaction
- Implemented full CRUD capability for user accounts/password info
- Added React-Bootstrap and custom CSS for style and overall look of the app

# Movie App- Github | Demo

Movie review App which allows users to see a list of movies from our server, to search and favorite movies.

- Users are able to view and add/create new movie details to our database
- Users can add movies to a separate favorites list they would like.
- Utilized Json Server for back end framework
- Used React for front end/client side rendering and interaction
- Added React-Bootstrap and custom CSS for style and overall look of the app

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **High Point Design**

New York,NY

Apparel Production Manager (Hosiery/Legwear)

04/2016 - 08/2022

- Managed, trained, and supervised Production Assistant on all tasks they are assigned(communication, approvals, and issues with factory and vendors)
- Worked with production team members to oversee all time and action calendars and production /order charts
- Coordinate with design, testing/compliance, sales, traffic, and accounting teams for each shipment and order

### Thread Collective Inc. / Billion Tower International LLC

New York, NY

Pre-Production/Order Entry

12/2014 - 04/2016

- Worked with Production Approval Manager to assist with pre-production QC & approvals
- Worked with Sales/Design/Merchandising team to create, update and maintain order details for all customer orders
- Oversaw and helped train order entry team in maintaining and processing order formats and fabrications details

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Flatiron School**

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, React.js and JavaScript program

08/ 2022 - 12/2022

#### **University of Delaware**

Bachelor of Arts, International Relations Japanese Minor